<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World! on My blog</title>
    <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello World! on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project II: Violence Detector</title>
      <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>For this example project I built a violent activity classifier to identify violence from non-violence scenes. This could be useful for communities or city management to take actions against violence from happening. They could monitor from cctv camera around the public places and an app could alert them about the activity prior. This is the underlying model for building something with those capabilities.
I was able to get the model to predict the violent activity with 94% accuracy after minimal tuning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project I: EDA of Amazon best selling books</title>
      <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that analyzes data of best selling books of Amazon. Collected amazon top 50 best selling books dataset from Kaggle resources. Processed data, Engineered features from the text of each job description to quantify the value companies put on python, excel, aws, and spark. Visualized top 15 Authors with highest number of Books Published, Author who published more than five books, 15 Books with highest user ratings, Sorted Books according to user rating, Top 10 Authors with highest reviews   Top 10 best selling books   Link to Github respository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project III: Hand Gesture Recognizer</title>
      <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that recognizes human hand movements using classification models. run the model in Unity to perform character animation based on the output of the model. Used teachable machine for training image classification model and imported the model to a local repo Implemented different hand gesture in real-time by using OpenCV. send the data to unity platform using socket module - configured animation   Illustration of hand gesture recognition in Unity   Link to Github respository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project IV: Home Surveillance System</title>
      <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that recognizes unauthorized human movements using OpenCV and classification models. Process the frames and apply background subtraction and object detection model stream the results to web browser developed using flask and Django. Implemented motion detector algorithm that detects motion by form of background subtraction.   Illustration of home Surveillance   Link to Github respository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isandeep4.github.io/Sandeep_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>   Follow me on these social media platforms.      Platform URL   Website: https://www.sandeepmyspace.com   Twitter: https://twitter.com/Sandeep74175175   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandeep/   Medium: https://medium.com/@isandeep   GitHub: https://github.com/isandeep4    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
